Now that we've managed to count the number of rolls,
بما أننا تمكنا الآن من حساب عدد الرميات،
we need to get two dice to match.
علينا الحصول على ناتج متطابق لحجري نرد.
Let's see what we need to do to add one more dice to
لنرى ما علينا فعله لإضافة نرد آخر لمشكلتنا،
our problem and count the rolls we need to get three dice to match.
وحساب عدد الرميات التي نحتاجها للحصول على نتيجة متطابقة لثلاثة أحجار نرد.
The first thing we need to do is declare this new variable integer dice3
أول شيء علينا فعله هو تعريف هذا المتغير الجديد هنا: int dice3،
here and set it to the return value of another roll dice call.
وتعيين قيمته بقيمة نتيجة رمي نرد آخر.
We also need to do that inside a while loop.
علينا أيضاً فعل ذلك داخل حلقة while.
When we re-roll our three dice,
عندما نعيد رمي أحجار النرد الثلاثة،
we need to set dice3 to be equal to another call of the roll dice function.
علينا تعيين قيمة "dice3" لتكون مساوية لنتيجة دالة رمي النرد.
Now the last thing we need to do is change
آخر شيء علينا فعله
instead of just two.
بدلاً من مجرد حجرين.
Unfortunately, we can't do something like this where we say,
لسوء الحظ، لا يمكننا فعل شيء كهذا، بحيث نقول:
dice1 equal to dice2, equal to dice3.
dice1 == dice2 == dice3.
Any comparison in Java can only have two sides.
لا يمكن لأي مقارنة في Java أن تحتوي على أكثر من طرفين فقط.
Otherwise, Java would complain and throw
وإلا سيحتج Java ويُظهر خطأ
an error before it even allows you to run that code.
حتى قبل أن يسمح لك بتنفيذ ذلك الكود.
However, we could use the logical operations that we've
لكن يمكننا استخدام العمليات المنطقية
learned in the previous lesson and break this check
التي تعلمناها في الدرس السابق وتجزئة عملية التحقق هذه
here into multiple checks into one condition like these options here.
إلى عدة عمليات تحقق في حالة واحدة، مثل هذه الخيارات هنا.
They're all correct as far as Java is concerned,
كلها صحيحة بالنسبة لـJava،
but only one of them would actually make our loop work the way we want it to.
لكن أحدها فقط سيجعل حلقتنا تعمل بالطريقة التي نريدها.
So which one of them do you think this loop condition should be?
أي واحد منها ينبغي أن تكون حالة الحلقة برأيك؟
Remember that now, we want the loop to keep going
تذكر أننا نريد أن تستمر الحلقة
as long as the three dice don't all match.
طالما لا تتطابق أحجار النرد الثلاثة.
Or in other words,
أو بكلمات أخرى،
once all three dice match,
حالما تتطابق أحجار النرد الثلاثة،
the loop should not go any longer.
ينبغي أن تتوقف الحلقة.